[Music]
you're watching The Breakfast
Club morning everybody it's DJ EnV
Angela ye charlam the God We Are The
Breakfast Club we have a special guest
in the building the homie Amanda
Diva Amanda Diva
BSA Amanda Diva B this is Amanda
seals Amanda Divas lives in Harlem
Amanda is in Hollywood that is a good
way to start though cuz I always love
the story of why you got rid of Amanda
Diva I just well there was a couple
things I she fought a long time for
getting rid of it you tell her own
story he's just making it know like I've
know you for a long time [ __ ] I've know
you for a long time for a long time he
really I he knows this yes I really did
but um no I turned like 30 and it just
felt stupid uh CU was like what are you
really doing little young Diva yeah
little young Diva and then you know who
really was on my back crazy like you
used to be on my back about it but you
let up you know who never let up Green
Lantern really never greenan like years
and years and years and on my 20 like
the night before I turned 30 he called
me at 11:30 and was like you changing it
right you changing it right and I was
like y get off my back and at the time I
was doing a web series on black voices
for AOL and I was trying to get
interview with whiz and I couldn't get
an interview at whiz but Quincy Jones
was like I'd love for you to interview
me and and green was like but you see
that's a testament to why you got to
change the name cuz you are trying to
elevate to to interviewing folks that
are already Legends not just be stuck in
in in this hip-hop [ __ ] and I was like I
mean I guess yeah like whatever I guess
so but you know but here was the final
Catalyst a week later I went to an event
and the chick at the door was like
what's your name and I said um it's
Amanda Diva and she goes yes [ __ ]
yes I was like
all all right I'mma Let It Go bad stigma
to Diva or something yes yes when we
were doing POV hip-hop POV on MTV I got
a call and was like okay so your job is
to come in here and prove you're not a
diva I was like but that no that's not
that's not my job but the preconceived
notion and you know there was just like
an it was like an albatross around my
neck and I'm already just not here for
the [ __ ] so you attach that to the
word Diva and it becomes [ __ ] and it's
just like you're fighting before you
even walk in the door I always felt that
was weird because people would always
say am this got an attitude but to me
you just don't take no [ __ ] well that's
cuz you speak your mind the same people
say that you are an [ __ ] so but let's
be clear now Amanda true though Amanda
has actually at one point or another
worked with all of us we've all been
co-workers can I tell yall a touching
story yes okay about y'all Okay Go Okay
so I came here in October of 2013 and I
was doing a onew woman show and uh I
came here and after I left here and
seeing y'all I cried for a whole day wow
and my mom was visiting and she was like
what's wrong with you you know West
Indian parents you can't cry so she's
like what's wrong with you and I was
like I don't even know and the next day
I don't even know I don't even know I'm
just I'm going through it I'm a cancer
I'm feeling feelings and the next
morning I woke up and I knew what it was
and I was like you know what I've known
all of them for so long and they had
found their home and they had found like
their their passion and they had found
their purpose and I was still
floundering and it was like I was crying
because of being in inspired by y'all
but it also was like a mirror to show me
like [ __ ] get it together and then that
day I created my web series things I
learned this week and even though like
it never got crazy views what it did was
it created a home for me as a comedian
and it was where I honed my skills as a
writer and as a comedian and that's how
my agent who ended up signing me to ca
that's how she found me amazing what
made you so thanks leave New York and go
to LA because that's a big
jump you just packed up and left right
no I mean it was time like a lot of
people don't know I was in hip-hop with
y'all for years right and then I started
transitioning and I was always like a
funny broad but then I like P started
pursuing like doing standup and then
once I was really in the mix of standup
it just became like a natural thing to
go to La and I would I went to LA for
the first time and I got more done in
one week than I had gotten done in a
year that makes sense in New York and I
was like okay so maybe you need to spend
more time here and so I had a lot of
miles and I would go every two months
and I'd be able to get tickets for like
$11 but every time I would go I would
just make so much Headway and then in
February
2015 my building the the pipes froze
like and y'all know I live in the same
building forever yes in Harlem the pipes
froze she was crazy my mom was visiting
me like the the we had no heat and no
water for two weeks her and the cat was
in the was quarantined in my room and I
went I went out to LA for a meeting and
I was sitting on Santa Monica beach and
my mother sent me a picture and the
toilet had Frozen yikes no need to come
back to that and I literally I replied
back and I said I'm moving and she's
like go for it mans and that was that
and I just started the process of come I
came back out here I found my my spot
but out to LA but also like I kept
meeting people that just were like go go
go like I ran into Issa and she was like
there's a community out here come out
here like the head of casting at ABC uh
this head of casting for like all these
yeah Tommy Tommy what's up Tommy Good
Old Tommy Crump was like Amanda get it
together like do it and when casting
people tell you you don't work make the
move but it was also like New York had
i' i' had my time is a real Renaissance
woman just thinking about everything
that you've done because you started off
acting at a young age and then you were
hosting you know as a VJ then you had
your own radio show then you were
actually doing music I always wanted you
to pursue more radio I'm not going to
lie everything comes back and then she
started her own series but what I love
is that when you felt like there was an
Elaine for what it is that you were
doing at the time you created it you
said I'm going to do my own series and
I've always gone on whatever it is
you're like come on always I'm always
there you do you do no but that's like
my mom I keep bringing up my mom cuz
like she's been a my mom says hi Envy by
the way like tell Envy hello um just
tell you Amanda is the only one that
used to bring her mom to work all the
time we get in trouble for bringing her
mom to work for bringing your mom to
work cuz why why why did I get in
trouble because where were we and
because who was there we're at Serious
XM and who got fired I'm tell us the
story out of here tell us the story what
happened I bring my mom to work all the
time too though you know what happened
Amanda would bring her mom to work
sometimes and her mom was West Indian
lady very nice very cheer [ __ ] your
mother oh no not that type no oh okay
no suck your mother but she would always
get in trouble for it and uh the other
week trouble for that yeah she would get
in trouble for I get written up for it
written up for it so the other week I
seen Amanda laughing on her Instagram
like this evil laugh like I'm like what
the hell she was like I just found out
my boy my ex-boyfriend is not doing well
damns and then she
said petty ass she said and then she
said I found out my ex my ex uh boss
just got
fired what's wrong with you that's the
first thing I said what's wrong with you
so explain the story now no you
know
I used to work at Sirius and the boss
and listen when I got my job at Sirius I
was only 22 no I was 21 it was my first
job out of college so when I think back
to what 21 was though like you're an
idiot you know you think you know [ __ ]
but you're still a young person trying
to figure it out and so like I'm you
know like maybe not turning in my
invoices right away and you know just
trying to find my footing and envy was
there and would help me like you know
okay do this do that like you know talk
to these people but I was just literally
just trying to get my footing in the
real world and this grown ass man had
made it his mission to just just Hound
me and make life difficult literally the
first day we met first of all anytime
you go to DAP someone and they give you
the
corporate sketchy yeah yeah you know
sketchy not even letting not even
letting you know that they down right
like he he literally said keep it
corporate and I'm like okay Annie had a
Annie had a little ass chain you know
what I'm saying so the
combinations
the combination why you why you got a
choker be why you got a Cuban Link
choker I ha I don't understand so fast
forward we had to have one on-one
meetings in my very first one-on-one
meeting he said to me you're spoiled and
I'm going to expose you whoa what like
and I'm literally like a 21y old just
out of college like this is my new boss
and that's what he says to me and in
hindsight like you don't you don't have
at that age a lot of times you don't
have the footing to be able to be like
I'll show him you know you're just like
[ __ ] I got to make him like me you know
so I would bring my mom to try and like
create like a familial type of um
familiarity and then like look like I'm
cool see look it's my mom I'm letting
you in and everything was copasetic
until I joined flry which is another
conversation we get into that we get to
that
one
and I you know I can't hide [ __ ] on my
face godamn it and once I joined FL tree
all all [ __ ] flipped over because then
he was like oh she's gonna be she's
gonna be famous yeah and then he like
shut everything down like all the niess
got shut down and then he was like no
like I'm he would lie to me like he
would say that people weren't coming in
when they really were coming in then I'd
have Like Rappers texting me like why
aren't you here I usually interview with
you and he's like other people need a
shot at stardom you're too you're too
you're too much other people need a shot
and let me tell y'all something can't
nobody take from you what's yours you
you know because even though he tried it
mhm who's here there you go and who's
fired who's sitting home watching this
right now seething I see you n mad that
you called his name and said he wear
choker well I will say that a lot of
times in our past I'm sure we could all
say this we've had experiences that have
been terrible at work and the best uh
thing to do is to be successful cuz that
is the best revenge absolutely on
anybody now you were a member of flry at
one point we had Mara up here I know she
told everybody told me yeah she told the
story she didn't have anything say about
oh okay well now actually the reason
that Amanda was INF flry
because you said because up you set it
up yeah so what happened was a shout out
to my boy Ryan Press Ryan hit me and
said we're looking for a female rapper
singer you know she could sing she could
rap somebody to join flry and go on tour
so I said oh my girl Amanda she's you
know she's literally get a text on my
side kick side text Amanda like her side
are you interested you think you would
want to join flow tree and she's like
yes so we get on the phone I hook it up
now mind you I thought it was just an
audition that they had other people but
they put her in the group like right
away so what happened with flry what was
so what was good and what was bad why
was you and Mar about to fist
fight it's abundance of questions first
of all I don't fist fight um because
that's not my forte I don't do things
that I'm not good at I'm a verbal
fighter so that's that um there was just
a certain level of dishonesty in terms
of like what I was walking into and I
didn't have the proper representation
also to have my back and you just it's
very hard when you don't have people
that really support you because then
you're getting set up and if you don't
have people that support you they're
just like let them set you up it's fine
just be just be happy you're getting the
shot and uh you know we we went on the
road and they didn't tell the fans mhm
that Natalie had left wow so you just
got in there like who's this and I don't
look like Natalie not at all right and
so much of flry was about their look you
know and the uniqueness of their look
and then here I come this high yellow
skinny [ __ ] you know and it's like
who's who's who's this and y'all like
I'm talking about in Baltimore a chick
swiped my ankle I had to like I had to a
yes I had to literally be like oh [ __ ]
you know like in um in in DC at love
at the start of the show everyone had
their backs to the stage like in protest
of me and every show I'd have to win the
crowd over and my frustration with Mara
was that she did not take an active role
in bringing me to the crowd with the
love that she would have needed to show
me for them to show love like she had
all the power to be like all right y'all
it's flowerry but it's different now you
know and we've got you know Natalie went
her own way but we're going to still
keep the Vibes going
and um so you just was out there girl
every every single show she would come
with a new way to come out and it would
never be that it was like okay so I'm
going to start singing butterflies and
then you're going to just come out and
give the band a pound like give
everybody a pound and then you're just
going to like come to the mic and start
singing and I'm like what what is that
setting you up for why set me up because
I remember they announced it I remember
seeing the Pres I have theories they
didn't announce it until the fifth the
no they announced the tour but they
didn't announce the situation and then
in Atlanta I was at soundcheck and I
mean I guess we on The Breakfast Club
this is where the te- spills right right
okay so little did everyone know that
prior to all of this me and the music
director were [ __ ] so prior to all of
this like we were already we had a
relationship okay but no one knew that
and so she's doing shady [ __ ] and he's
like coming back and telling you yes oh
pillow talking okay homie talk F
so so you know and that's the thing it's
like don't be Shady you know like that's
it like don't be Shady so what's your
theory why would she do that why would
she cuz my the understanding what she
wanted to keep it going let me get my
theory is that they wanted me to quit so
that she could finish out the tour as
just like a Mara tour under the flry
banner mhm that's my setting up her solo
career yes that's my theory and I was
about to leave in Atlanta because
homeboy told me like yo she's trying to
cut your solo song from the show but we
had just done soundcheck and she had
never mentioned that so literally what
would have happened is I would have been
on stage and the part of the show where
my song is supposed to come another song
would have just come on and I wouldn't
you been looking crazy yes and so I I
said something to her about it and she
was just like just you know rebuffed me
and then when I got to my room I
remember Dwight wiy shout out to Dwight
Dwight Dwight Dwight texted me and was
like turn on Wendy Williams turn on
Wendy Williams and Natalie was on there
and I was like she was just going hard
and was like Amanda seals is not flow
tree flow tree is Mara and not late and
if you're going to the show just know
that I'm going to be there I'm going to
be there so I'm like I call Marsha's
room like what's going on and you know
like you know when you need a certain
response to feel comfortable I didn't
get that response like I didn't get like
a no girl it's me and you I got like a
yeah I don't know player and I was like
damn I was like I'm out I'm out and so I
I was just y'all know me like I once I
he that point You' you've witnessed and
Amanda seals I'm out I witnessed me and
Andrew were doing an event one time and
I found out she was getting paid and I
wasn't I was like I'm out
um and yeah and so I was about to leave
and the drummer is actually who stopped
me like everybody else who hit me about
leaving was was given wrong reasons to
stay but the drummer was like
listen they want you to leave and if you
leave you're giving into them you're
giving into their negativity you're
giving into their expectations that you
are weak and if you stay what you're
showing is that you're going to
persevere regardless and honestly he was
like this is about your journey like
don't don't let them steer you off your
journey and he's so right because after
that you know me and Marsha we ended up
like coming to an understanding and then
we finished the tour but what I did
learn on that tour is like Mara is an
incredible vocalist and in and in the
studio like her ability to stack vocals
and you know make Melodies was
incredible so I got to learn from one of
the greats in that respect and it really
changed my music you know and also
anytime you get to be on the road and
going in different cities and doing your
art you're learning every different city
and that's what I had said when me and
Amanda we had a lot of conversations
during that time and I was like this is
a great experience for you to learn how
to be a better performer for your solo
performances and for people to learn who
you are and I know there was a lot of
drama going on but I'm glad you're stuck
at that well cuz I'm not I mean honestly
like I'm not a selfish person so it's
like I don't naturally think about like
how's this going to serve me you know
it's like people have to be like Amanda
uh like you can win here I'm like oh
yeah okay cool cool cool now after you
left the group did you keep [ __ ] the
music
director yes yeah but on I mean like
over years of time because he's a [ __ ]
[ __ ] but now Amanda let's talk about
relationship few minut because that's
another thing that
Amanda always gets into is a lot of f
boys out here right and are you I mean
it's hard not to you've always been so
vocal about your relationships like even
when we used to work at hip hop po I
used to be hearing things I know I
wasn't supposed to be hearing but then I
end vocal about stuff yeah yeah I one
like I just had a orgasm for the first
time it was exciting like this it's like
2010 2012 because like it's not
necessarily easy to have an orgasm from
a dick right wow especially if someone
hasn't made it their business like it
requires like it's not just like a
general area thing you got to nail it
it's like a sniper thing do you think
sex could still be good if you don't
have an orgasm at this point for me no
because then I know what I'm missing
right
but you know what s because it doesn't
happen every time I still remember
exactly what this guy looked like
because what does penis look like shut
up cuz she she kept pointing him out
like that's the guy that gave me my
first
or he was from Philly I know I remember
him wow don't give him too much I won
okay I won't beard let's not even do
this I don't remember his name though I
what he looks
like shut up no cuz he's that dude like
he would use my name to get into places
I gave man an orgasm Tiffany du I gave
her an
orgasm so what's your relationship St is
now cuz I'm sure a lot of f boys in the
past have been coming out the wood my
God like termites they're just like
eating up the Woodworks um hey what's
good yo and my favorite is yo I'm proud
of you you ain't proud of me I always
knew that's my version of hey Big Head y
I'm proud of you I'm proud of you girl I
see you shining shut
up used to be used to be a host on
Direct effects too right no sucker free
Sucker Free she's the first after allot
on them yep me and you allegedly got
both fired by
Jay-Z Mom did you hear that I didn't yo
that's my mother's Theory that's been my
mother's theory for years I could never
prove it let's talk about it cuz the
story was that you were doing an
interview
and you wanted Jay-Z on your album
that's what it was Jay-Z on your album
and you asked Jay-Z for his number this
the story yeah this the story and you
asked Jay-Z for his number and the
people at MTV thought that was
disrespectful and let you go I never
thought anything was wrong with that by
the
way let me look dead in this camera and
tell y'all that that is not I mean I'm
do you see this genuine you never heard
that befuddlement you never heard this
story I've never heard this story I mean
I don't know I wasn't there so I have
why Mama think you got fired by Jay-Z
because my mom be knowing your mom be
knowing and there was just there was
always like too many situations where it
was like hoves there and then funny
stuff happened with me that's happened
like three different times yeah like I
got in trouble at Sirius one time
because he was sitting there in the
lobby and I was like what you doing he
was like nothing I was like you want to
do an interview because you know how
serious was like you just had a studio
and he was like serious us deated to the
the popping white people not really the
urban so we had to get in where we fit
in so if we seen the a we going snatch I
got a lot of interviews cuz I was on at
the same time as Howard Stern yeah but
you said he said sure he said sure and
was like where you where you want to go
and we did the interview and the next
day I got written up and they were like
you know you did an unauthorized
interview yeah that happened to me with
Sean Carter I would feel like that's
really going for it and I texted him I
texted him I was like you know I just
got in trouble for interviewing you and
he was like I I would think you would
get a pat on the
back but wait let me just tell let me
clarify this is what happened at
mtv2 the first time I was interviewing
him it was to promote uh Fade to Black M
and he was there and he was waiting for
his jewelry to come so he was just
sitting in the um in the waiting area
and we were just waiting and they were
like well do you want to come and talk
to him so you can kind of just like
build a rapport before you do the
interview and I was like sure and I had
an original copy an original vinyl of uh
Volume One MH and of Reasonable Doubt no
I had original copy of Reasonable Doubt
okay and so I came and I just showed it
to him like this is how much of a fan I
am you know and he was like oh do you
want me to sign it
yeah yeah sure there was a Sharpie right
there he signed
it that's that's the story that's the
whole story that's got in trouble for
that the next day I got a call from my
boss and he was like you know what you
did with Jay-Z was very inappropriate
and I was like what did I what what did
I do with with with Hove and he was like
well you know we told you not to take
any
pictures and I was like I but I didn't
take any pictures he said well signing
the album is the same thing wow that's
what
and I was like okay and then about a
month later they fired me so who even
told them that you like that you got a
son who
told there was a John that was TV there
was a there was a John there who I had
been told like was a hater or whatever
you know I mean I was always like the
young loud chick so it was offensive to
people a lot of issues like with women
in the workplace because I see a lot of
women supporting you now right and you
have your whole Community but has has it
been like that always or do you feel
like it's harder for you I think I'm
just a big personality and I think that
gets misread like even like coming up in
college like it's like oh you just like
you're too much you're too much you know
what I mean and so I think it's like
it's like growing into it's like growing
into your looks I kind of had to grow
into my personality like you were always
a breath of fresh air because you were
always just kind like an has always been
a supporter you've always been just
regular even when they were trying to
pit us against each other
yes as serious as serious oh yeah it was
like yeah you know she's trying to take
your slot you know she and and and then
you'd be like hey you want to come on
the show so it's like well clearly she's
not I mean listen I from when I first
met Amanda I thought she was super cool
we had no issues we used to hang out
super cool super talented smart I always
said Amanda is so talented like I I
couldn't I didn't know what you would
end up doing but I was like she's so
talented obviously I thought that CU I
would recommend you for anything
anything so I mean I think but honestly
like if I'm really thinking back it's
been women in the workplace who have
always helped me like it was it was my
boss at bet that changed my life that
made me able to move to LA cuz I I woke
up one day in 2014 and did not know
where my next check was coming from like
legit just was like oh wait how did I
let this happen again and then I I hit
up this woman shaie that I had you know
done some work with that bet and I was
like hey I'd love to come in and just
like pitch some ideas to you for digital
she was like yeah come through and I
came in I pitched an idea for like a a
web series it's like a celebrity fashion
like fun like thing called funny style
and she was like okay let's do a pilot
so we did a little pilot and then she's
like okay let's do six episodes and we
did six episodes and I came in her
office I said listen you know I need to
change my life and the only way that I'm
going to be able to change it is with a
steady flow of income I need to move to
LA and I need support in order to do
that and she was like well I want to be
a part of your success so I'll pick up
your web series for a year wow and she
kept her word and even when I moved to
LA she made it possible for me to change
the format so that I could do it in LA
you know and it was like it was one of
those Alchemist moments where it's like
you know like an if you build it they
will come like I had decided I needed to
move and then all the pieces just
started like falling into place and
making it possible for me to move and
once I got to La you know everything is
just kind of you guys have known me for
a long time so you've seen like damn
like she literally moved there a year
and a half and everything has just been
like turning over and stuff that I've
always been doing is now being
recognized you know by by like
legitimate credible sources and places
and it's really it's cool but people
don't see those years of hard work that
you was putting in way prior to La no I
mean the beauty is that we have the
internet so if you want to see those
years you can find them like now you you
had to school Caitlyn Jenner on uh being
a minority in America and and his
privilege that was a beautiful moment
her privilege her privilege what
happened with
that you know what ask that over just in
case just you ask over when you say her
privilege please she corrected me we
good stop being so scary we're learning
it's the process relax Jesus Christ
continue Miss seals her privilege um so
I went to this Katy Perry dinner that I
was invited to they were having this
like dinner of discourse where they
wanted to focus on like how it is to
have difficult
conversations and everyone there was
very nice and um you know very congenial
but it was also just like are we just
going to sit here and like Pat each
other on the back like I don't know the
purpose of this if we're not going to
have like actual discourse and if you
saw the live stream you saw that over
the course of the stream they kept like
getting on me because I would be the one
as usual pointing out like hey that
don't make sense hey what are you
talking about and Kaylin Jenner
she be trying to glamour folks you know
what I'm saying like cuz
she's she a vampire it's true she's
trying to suck the the Consciousness out
of you man like sounds
appealing cuz she's sitting there and
you you know you've you've already been
shown like okay like she's gone through
this journey and you've been shown this
transgender moment but like it makes you
forget that like okay but you're also
for a long time you've been this very
privileged white man you've been a part
of the Kardashian family like that
doesn't just go away right like that
doesn't just get erased like you killed
somebody in a car accident like that
doesn't just and you and and nothing
happened to you that is white privilege
right like and so long story short over
the course of the dinner like she just
kept saying stuff that was so ridiculous
like so white Manish yeah like oh you
know I'm I'm I'm mean I'm working with
the Republicans from the inside on the
things that they're not good at and I
said well what are they good at and
she's like well you know I I I'm having
a hard time helping the the Democrats
and I said but but what are the
Republicans good at mm then she said
something else and I was like you
realize you've said the same thing three
times and they're like
Amanda don't go hard on her and
eventually what ended up happening was
someone said that Donald Trump will pass
meaning what's that mean like die no
just like his yeah like it's gonna come
and go you know it'll pass and I was
like you know I'm sure there were people
that thought the same thing about Hitler
and they were like whoa and sometimes
you do have to hit people with an
extreme example for them to even see you
know a modum of what you're trying to
say but it did wake them up and they
were like well how can you say that and
I said well you know it's not like he
hasn't shown through example his
propensity for evil and then he's not
just him he has a whole staff you know
Pence Bannon Ryan this divor broad all
of these people are actively doing work
to undermine equality to undermine
inclusivity to undermine educational
resources etc etc etc so why we acting
brand new and they were like well
Caitlyn what do you think and she was
like I just don't want to talk anymore
CU it's just the conversation's too
hostile really it's just it's too
hostile and I was
like and I was like what like what and
that's when the conversation turned
thank you to me um saying you know it's
actually thanks to Van Jones van Jones
was like well you can't just shut it
down like that and I said well you know
I'm not hostile I'm passionate and I
should be able to be we come from
different backgrounds and people after
this conversation where I told Caitlyn
Jenner essentially like we don't come
from like America hasn't treated you the
same way that it treats black people and
of course she was like she scoffed which
is that's just willful ignorance like
it's willful ignorance you're not even
listening and we and why do we act like
Jim Crow didn't happen like recently
like there are people alive and well
right now that live through Jim Crow
yeah the Civil Rights Act of 19 was
signed in 1964 like people are still
trying to get their first crush in
college and you're 52 and you're still
thinking about that [ __ ] but you're
trying but you're expecting black people
to get over 400 plus years of legal
oppression cuz let's be real like Jim
Crow was is lawful right now at least
you can maybe file a civil rights suit
and be like hey you know they did this
[ __ ] no back then it was legal and so uh
the beauty of it though
was I feel like it's really a blessing
especially in in this day and age where
like you never know what camera's on you
you never know what what where they're
going to catch you you know the internet
or whatever it's a real blessing to like
get notoriety being your best self right
like that was living in your truth
living in your truth which is what I'm
all about and like um like my Instagram
following went up from 44,000 to 111,000
in four days wow and that really is a
testament to like how hungry people are
for the truth and how hungry people are
for you know black women being honest
and and raising our voices in the face
of people like Caitlyn Jenner because
someone like Caitlyn Jenner she's not an
influencer and that's the thing people
think oh she's an influencer what's she
influencing all she's influencing is you
to watch because you're trying to figure
out what the [ __ ] is going on right but
she's not using any of her uh clout to
change anything that's she had to make
America great ahead great again hat on
the other day get out of here like
people like that should use their
privilege to combat the prejudices that
are going on in the world world not
reinforced them but they don't
acknowledge they have privilege right in
that same thing she was like the worst
time of my life was cutting my hair I'm
like oh oh my
goodness were there any conversations
after the dinner like when the camera
stopped rolling like of course oh you
know cuz then they whenever you're the
black girl in the room everyone does
want to be cool with you right this
always happens they come up to you after
like hey girl you go girl they ask you
about your hair and uh she had come up
to me and was like you know I just want
you to know like I am working from the
inside you know I'm just like okay great
okay you know now let's talk about what
else you have going on now you also have
this weekly um no this monthly column
that you're doing right for Harper's
Bazaar weekly oh it's weekly mhm okay so
you just started that I just started
that you bosted up at True TV though
that's that didn't happen again I bossed
out oh what happened with True TV I sold
my show smart funny and black to True TV
and then it just wasn't
demographically a fit and so we're back
in the mix and we're pitching and it's
exciting because I didn't get a chance
to pitch the show uh the first round I
was already at True TV you know I was
doing uh greatest ever and they did like
a fantastic ad Campaign which you know
thank you and um they were really behind
me and so they were like what are you
working on I said well I've created this
game show it's a black pop culture game
show uh that talks about Black Culture
black history and the black experience
because I'm tired of seeing all these
negative images of us so let's do a
celebration and and uh I started doing
it in in New York I mean in la every
month at uh this place called nerd melt
every first Tuesday we sell out every
month we've had guests you need to come
and do it uh if you're in town whenever
any of 18th or 19th any of y'all can do
it um TV is idiots so Jesus Christ how
y'all let that
go and
so but the show it like we've had Lil R
and Tiffany hadish on the show we've had
JLS and Issa Reay we've had orgy and Lon
Kerman last month we had um Lamor Morris
and Damon wayin Jr like we've I mean
we've had just like this incredible cast
of folks that come through because
especially in La they're just a't a lot
of black stuff and like it's a testament
to like people really enjoy doing the
show and it's educational but it's funny
as [ __ ] and uh so now I've gotten to
come out and pitch it which has been
really exciting to like get in the room
and you know I thank I thank True TV
because I got an opportunity listen when
I left here it was like I want to sell
shows I want to sell shows like and
congrats to you just I feel like every
other day Charlamagne has sold a new
show I'm like this Negro here yes yes
and you know we should talk
okay we should definitely talk and I
wanted to sell shows and so you know it
is a big [ __ ] deal to sell a show and
I didn't realize that like I thought it
was just like if the show doesn't get on
TV it doesn't matter and everyone was
like no like people don't even get a
chance to get in the room oh let alone
to get a show sold let alone to get a
pilot shot you know so um and thank you
to just like my teammate at brillstein
at CIA because they believe in me and
I've had so many representatives that
never believed in me that told me like
just be happy they want you you know
like I didn't I didn't send you out
there to get you rich whereas these
folks are like whatever happens you
always going to be straight like and and
when I told them like listen we're about
setting precedences like I don't want to
hear oh can't do that cuz this didn't
work for somebody else if anything we
should look at why it didn't work for
that other person and use that to make
it work for us and they use that I feel
like it's this Renaissance happening
it's like uh all of these these these
black women who've been grinding for so
long are starting to get their just do
you mentioned Tiffany we see it with you
like what do you think it
is I mean I think also like remember our
generation grew up watching Living
Single and watching different world and
we grew up watching black women on TV
being funny and then there was just this
like
Dar where we were just not there and it
just need we just needed time to get our
shot to be able to bring that back you
know and I think once they see how
successful it can be also then all of a
sudden everybody's looking to cash in on
that we the number one
consumers black women are the number one
consumers of like everything we make
everything
Trend this trending is because we're
watching it we're paying attention to it
and we're talking about it and it's the
internet absolutely and like just seeing
how people have responded to insecure
how people responded to Atlanta you know
and just and queen sugar like these
shows definitely Inspire the rest of us
to like okay keep pushing keep pushing
keep pushing so smart funny and black
you going to see it soon because that's
just how things work my wife watches it
all the time watches what she used to
watch more funny and black when it was
online all the time all the time nice
now let's discuss insecure and how all
that happened for how that come about
because your show was on Issa Ray's
channel right she had a channel on
YouTube so I had a web series called get
your life and uh I shot that like while
I was in LA and then the second season
Charlamagne actually donated to our
crowd fund so thank you very much how
much you donate why does it matter
$1,500 that's good I
know and no it does matter by the way
because trust me there's folks that
Penny pinched and I'm just like all
right there's folks that love to be like
yo I got you I got you I got you and
then they gave you $200 yeah and you're
like bro that's not even a Gucci shoe
like not even one shoe not a shoe not
even the pair that's not even one Gucci
shoe so I just um so I was doing get
your life and but a lot of people don't
understand like of course there's like
who you know but you still often times
have to go through certain protocols
like at the end of the day HBO is still
HBO so I didn't have any credits any
like uh non any scripted credits like
I've been hosting forever but I haven't
been like doing scripted since I was on
Nickelodeon since I was doing my brother
and me so I was starting from the bottom
in that respect and D we forgot about
that
my damn a young actor I've been sag
since '92 player sag since
92 and um and so I went in for the
audition but I originally went in for
Tasha and the the the breakout the
breakdown said Hood hot and I was like I
I don't have the proportions to fit that
description like you had to have a big
ass and all that like I have moderate
titties you know they're enough they're
not you know exponential but they're
solid and I have booty on the low booty
on the low booty on the low means you
don't know I got it till you got
it you take my right you're
like you know
so I'm proud of
you keep shining
girl the [ __ ] stars emojis and [ __ ]
out of here with a peach um and so I
definitely like I I remember going into
the audition I was like I can't to the
casting director I was like this ain't I
can't do this and she was like Amanda
you can play any part and I was like I
appreciate the support but it it I know
I know what I can as someone who's also
a writer and producer like when I read
roles I know it's not for me me and
Tiffany were the last two up for that
role for Girl trip and I was like why
are y'all making me do this this is
Tiffany's role all of us know that in La
like there's a small group of folks that
are auditioning we go to auditions
you're like hey Bo that's when you catch
up with folks and we'll all see a script
and know who this is for right I'll see
a script and be like this is Bia this is
PR web like this is this is Tiffany this
is Tiffany and so for this role I just
was like yeah like this is not me and
she goes well what do you do you want to
read for the other role and I was like
well what's the other role and she said
oh it's um early 30s ivy league graduate
you're like that's me I'm like you mean
my actual life and so I read for
that then you do another audition that
audition is for ISSA and apprentice and
Molina and you're in this little ass
room it is VE listen auditioning for
people you know is way more stressful
than auditioning for people you don't
know because they're
like they're just like staring at you
and you're trying to pretend like you
don't know them and then I had to do
another audition and then you do a
chemistry test where it's you and three
other chicks and then it's the other
dudes that will play your husband and
they just keep interchanging you MH and
I remember sitting outside the room when
this other chick went in and when she
went in the room they were all like hey
and I was like why am I even here
they're besties what's the point and um
and so I remember it was like a good two
weeks without hearing anything and I was
leaving my house to go do standup and I
got a text from Issa and it was a bunch
of white Applause hands she's the white
hands and I was like right and I was
like I don't know what white Applause
hands means like if they were black
Applause hands I feel like I would know
but white Applause hands might mean just
like good job you know like great great
try grind yeah keep grinding and so I
hit her back with like two question
marks and then she didn't respond she
didn't respond I'm in the car and I'm on
the phone with my mom I was like yeah
like I got this weird text from East I
don't know like you know what it means
and my mom why PL hands too she's in her
yeah I was like you know and my mom was
just like yeah I don't know and then as
I was on the phone with my mom I got a
text and she was like you're in and I
was like I almost crashed this car like
that's like a phone call I mean I feel
like it was it was on the you know I'm
probably blowing your spot up right now
but it uh it was one of those moments
though where you're like oh like things
are going to be different you know and
like I got to pay my mom's bills last
month that was very exciting you know
and uh but just since living in LA and
like doing show doing insecure and doing
my show smart funny and black and even
like my Instagram like my insta stories
like people come up to me all the time
like your in stories are very inspiring
you know they're they're helping me make
better decisions and [ __ ] like it's just
uh as a artist it's incredible to like
see folks see you and then be able to
give that back you know and be able to
like have enough money to send like
these two girls to this this you know
black girl empowerment camp that we're
trying to go and like be able to start
send two girls there mhm do and um
remember one time you told me you was
like nothing worth than being famous and
broke it makes no sense I was famous and
broke my whole life got cuz people
expect things from you and yes I was on
the bus and these chicks was like you me
in a diva and I was like
indeed they were like why you want the
bus though you know it's like I got to
go somewhere I got to get there you know
and in New York sometimes the bus is the
best route right I take the train all
the time FYI take the those people going
always be judgmental cuz you could be on
a plane now and they like why you on the
plane why you flying private right why
you in coach may your coach yeah now
let's talk about your dating life now I
knew she was going to bring it back see
I tried to evade her she asked earlier
she asked ear I tried to evade I saw
that you had one person on your vagenda
only so does that mean that you have a
boyfriend Venda is that a vagina agenda
tellan what my new word it's my new word
that I just made up your vagenda who's
on your Venda your Venda is your list of
individuals that you would like to give
your vagina to it's a vagina agenda your
Venda so you have one person on your
vagenda does that mean that you're in a
relationship
or
yes so hold on is this on Facebook like
I can go look at this like it's a
calendar
orenda Venda how does Angela know there
only one person on it cuz she said it on
Twitter oh okay got you how do I know I
mean I think relationship very loose
term these days you should do a Venda
[Music]
app why' you go uh oh no go ahead loose
terms go ahead relationship is loose go
ahead no I say that because as I've
gotten older you just see that pacing is
very very important when you say you're
in a relationship it's more serious than
when you were younger like when you're
younger I'd be like yeah that's my
boyfriend the how serious Ser is it like
did Mama meet him yet this is the first
she's hearing about this whoa oh so no I
mean it's just it's a situation that I
am
entertaining that's where we're at
that's where we're at like it's it's uh
y'all just having sex right now you just
[ __ ] so would he come to the family
cookout he would if I asked him to okay
he would got ask will he will she invite
him to the family cookout it's a process
all this is a process you know I got
money now I got to put [ __ ] through
[ __ ] what if you bring them to the
cookout I gotta be more picky now what
if bring him to the cookout and he
leaves the cookout early to go to a work
function and never comes
back how would you hand that
situation I mean honestly if that was a
situation that I knew ahead of time was
going to
happen I'm actually glad that you have a
work function to go to cuz let's be real
my last situation his work function was
going to my work functions and turning
up well he was giving you orgasms that's
a fair trade is
it is it you know carry in my bags after
I DJ like I'm here for a
reason you think you would ever get into
politics no I don't need to get into
politics I I can affect politics without
being a
politician you know so if that means
getting into politics for but I you can
be active I can be active yeah like I I
wouldn't be effective as a politician
I'm too real they would kill me I don't
mean like an actual politician let me
rephrase it like a political commentator
like how Angela Ry is all she been on
CNN right yeah I've been doing that I
mean but politics doesn't really
inpire me the way
that just social commentary in general
does you know because I feel like a lot
of times politics you get you get caught
up in like the names of these inse
inconsequential people that are really
just like toys for this the bigger 1%
that's really controlling [ __ ] and you
know it's it's just like it's just like
rat beef it's like you know you just
that's what you know and so it's fun to
just move interchange with that but I'm
more interested in just like bigger
picture
macro stuff which is like okay how is
this politics actually affecting people
you rather affect change on the ground
like yeah real things that you could see
with people that yes like that's why I
like young people you know like this
younger
generation
um and this is something the individual
that I'm talking to said so this is this
is to show you some of his intellect but
he was like you
know you're a
fool he was like you know this
generation if you notice like these kids
are different than us like they're just
a lot more generous you know like we
would be very much like mine mine mine
and they're just a lot more generous
they're a lot more intuitive they're
definitely way more techn
technologically advanced just by Nature
definitely you know and it's and it's
just like this generation of kids you
just see that like they are an open book
to be nurtured and to to take this world
to another level like I feel like all of
us are in this like middle generation
where like the web came in and you we're
just kind of a bridge but the real [ __ ]
is going to happen with the generation
under with the younger Generations
they're the ones that are going to be
really affecting change because
technology advances so quickly and so I
feel like our work is to really be about
like how are we affecting them and so
I'm very conscious about like the stuff
I put out people think I'm crazy why
because they think I don't have a filter
and it's like it's not that I don't have
a filter it's just that I'm not
filtering because of the same reason you
filtering okay you know like a lot of
people filter because of fear they
filter based on fear they filter based
on like I don't want people to not like
me they filter based on you know I don't
want people to I don't want to get fired
you know they filter and these are all
real
things but I just um I'm over it like I
did that for a long time and it's funny
Once I stopped doing that that's when
I've been able to have my most prolific
time and my most Freedom so for me it's
like I feel like that's part of my work
is encouraging in this younger
generation to speak up and giving them
tools on how to speak up and information
and encouraging folks to challenge [ __ ]
and ask questions and just encouraging
education you know that's interesting
you say that CU I feel like I was
thinking about this lately I feel like I
don't have a filter because I am afraid
I'm afraid that if I don't say what it
is God puts on my heart to say all of
this can be taken away from me I don't
think that's fear M I think that's just
purpose you just know your purpose it's
not like you're
I mean I don't feel like you're afraid I
mean you just said it but I don't know I
I just feel like that's just like I know
what I'm here to do and I got to do my
job yes you know and I'd feel the same
way too like when people say like how'd
you come up with that this at this point
I genuinely don't know like sheit just
be coming to me I'm like a satellite
like I'll literally just be in my house
sometimes you'll see me on my insta
stories when you see me like like you
just see this part up here I really am
naked
like like I really did just get out the
shower and was thought like I need and I
just need to say it you know and um and
that's like a legit thing and I just
feel like once you know that about
yourself you have like you have no
choice yeah you got to do it that's true
though more stuff comes when you get the
other stuff out yes and when you start
go like I went to therapy so right
before I moved to LA I went to therapy
therapy for
what like a therapist like uh a
cognitive behavioralist start seeing
that's what I'm about to start seeing
CBT so I went to a cognitive behavioral
therapist but I learned later that like
analysis may have also been helpful but
I went to a cognitive therapist because
she was referred to me and it's very
hard as a black woman to find a black
woman therapist they're out here I'm not
saying they're not out here but it just
it's tough but I went to her and I was
like you know I'm moving to LA and I
would love to just kind of like unpack
some things before I go because I feel
like when you get out there like you
need to be sturdy and she was like
um she just started talking to me and I
told her a story about how like someone
had literally just said to me like it's
great that you're moving to La cuz you
know people don't like you what and I
have been told say that to you girl and
I literally a dude told me that the
night before I moved on a
date and you know you watching right now
and I still remember D and he literally
he literally on the date was like I mean
you know people don't like you and I've
had to stand up for you for years and
I'm just like he thought that was a good
line that was good and listen he was on
the Venda it's my last night in New York
you on the Venda spending time with me
on my last night he didn't get all you
had to do I left him sitting right in
front the fountain that fountain in
front of 1221 that fountain in front of
Sirus across from Atlantic I left him
sitting right there and got on the train
I was like I'm good this is silly and
don't come to my going away party
neither my goodness but people like say
stuff like that and you're just like
what who are y'all people and people
kept telling me that so much I believed
it and I realized I did not like myself
like I had really like internalized like
damn like maybe I'm not likable and my
my therapist helped me to just be able
to see like the things that they were
saying that they didn't like she helped
me to pick those apart and acknowledge
what those things were and why they're
saying that and and find love in those
things again like no you're you're not a
diva you're not difficult you just
difficult to [ __ ] over you know what I
mean like you're not difficult you're
just part particular like you're not
demanding you just make people you hold
people accountable and you know you get
you get these things
misconstrued and people manipulate you
to feel like the things that are
actually positive are negative because
they simply are truths and people don't
like the truth that's why they say the
truth hurts and so she really helped me
to get over that and get clearer on like
what my strengths are and the things
that even though they are strengths that
are going to be misconstrued and how to
handle that and I needed it and I think
a lot lot of us were afraid to look at
ourselves cuz it's uncomfortable and you
know there is some [ __ ] that she told me
that is like yeah that's that's not the
best I have to work on that you know
like I like talking like my patience I
have no patience you know and like I
have no tolerance for stupidity so but
it's like you got to re like some people
have had different educational levels
and some people's brains work
differently like my brain works really
really fast but that doesn't make me
better that just is how my brain works
but if I'm speaking to somebody who
maybe that's not their gift
that doesn't make them less gifted you
just have to have more patience yeah you
got to be patient in matters where
others are involved because there was a
time that you who know knew
not
yes I mean I heard like
violins do your agents and stuff ever
tell you don't discuss politics Amanda
stay away from that n cuz when they met
me that's how they met me from doing my
web series things I learned this week
like listen I went and saw 12 Years a
Slave and 2012 and I came out the
theater and I literally stood in front
of Lincoln Center and I was like you
know what that's it I'm I'm going to
stop crossing over and I'm going to
break through and I'mma do it being as
black as I want to be which was counter
to everything anyone had told me even
your ass whoa and you told her not to be
black he didn't tell me not to be black
but he was just like yo like you can't
go hard like that I told her the D was
don't make me spell your name your
government name blackest [ __ ] in here
there's an apostrophe in this man lard
might there's a capital San is liquor
store Robin
Blacky a lot of people a lot of tea
getting spilled this morning all right a
minut so he told you you was to wrap it
up now he want to wrap it up this not a
new thing no no it's not that he told me
it's too black but it was all there's
always people around me there are just
like H like don't go so hard like it
comes from a place of Love they just
don't want me to get in my own way
that's all it's just and honestly
there's been examples of people going
hard and it getting in their own way you
know and like you look at Nina Simone
like that was a part of like why her
career didn't happen the way it happened
but it also there were other extenuating
circumstances I know for me I go hard
but I have a strong support base you
know and I have people that love me like
I know all y'all love me but if you were
a man here they'd be like you a boss and
you bought your [ __ ] yeah of of course
yeah but I have to be here to help
change that gotcha so I mean and like
the fact
that it's not just me saying this either
you know like there's a whole Squad of
folks that are that are out here and
it's not just women there are men that
are supporting us and there's trans
people everybody is like you know it's
time for a change it's time for a change
so you do that in your work you do that
in your presence and that's how I
operate like I don't do it on just one
thing like you're going to see it in the
scripted work I do in the non-script
unscripted work I do you're going to see
it in my digital work you're going to
see it in my standup you see it in this
interview because I just feel like I
need to embody it at all times and for
y'all to really know that the
authenticity is real well you've been
talented you've been a star and I feel
like like you're getting your just doe
now but your moment is yet to come your
moment's coming oh that's exciting no
it's your moment is coming definitely
I'm looking forward to that can can I
come back when the moment comes like o I
like that
coming
she already had that
moment let's end with this though you
often say you uh Liv in your truth I
like to say live your truth I'm sure us
the same thing but what does living in
your truth mean living in your truth
just means being honest with yourself
about yourself and for some people that
means that you're going to be facing
things about you that you may not like
and then it means that you might be
facing people that may not like what
they're seeing either and so with I'll
use the example with Caitlyn Jenner like
I'm at a table of people who may not be
receptive of my truth which is that as a
black woman I have a different opinion
of politics and of existing in America
the majority of these people at this
table right
and a lot of people would be afraid to
live in that truth in that space because
they feel like they might get attacked
or they might get you know deferred or
they might get dismissed and it's like
if you're not living in your truth
you're not going to be able to get to
where you're supposed to be and I
consider your truth to be your compass
to your purpose and if you're not living
in that truth then you are being steered
by other worldly things that don't
necessarily have your best interests at
heart Amanda seals ladies and gentlemen
Amanda congratulations Amanda on
everything everything and best has yet
to
there you go where can they follow you
and all that good stuff follow me at
Amanda seals on Twitter Amanda seals on
Instagram Amanda seals on YouTube I just
started a new web series on Harper
Bazaar that you can also see on my
YouTube called gem dropping I look out
for my book coming soon small doses
potent truths for everyday use when's
that
coming
and you can check me out uh on insecure
as Miss Tiffany Dubois right now in
season two and if you're in La come and
check out smart funny and black every
first Tuesday 9:00 p.m. at nerdmelt and
follow me on Instagram because we sell
out the same day that I posted on my
Instagram all right well Miss Amanda
seals it's The Breakfast Club good
[Music]
morning